《诉讼双雄》前情提要
迈克·罗斯从没上过法学院
Mike Ross never went to law school.
我知道  但我还是雇了他
And ‭I knew it, and I hired him anyway.
我还是不能留下来  哈维
I still can't stay, Harvey.
你弄的像是我夺走了
You're making it seem like I'm the one
你的梦幻婚礼一样
that's taking away your dream wedding.
本来就是你夺走了我的梦幻婚礼
You are the one taking away my dream wedding.
没什么能比让我
Nothing would make me happier
举杯庆祝你的新生活更能让我开心的
than to raise a glass to your new life,
但我不能
But I can't.
所以现在我不该结婚了
Oh, so now I shouldn't get married.
不  我是说你应该辞职
No, I'm saying you should quit.
所以你现在告诉我  你为什么来这里
You tell me right now, why are you here?
-一言难尽  -你为什么来这里
- It's not that simple. - Why are you here?
因为我害怕
Because I'm afraid!
你今天召集了紧急不信任投票
You're calling for an emergency vote of no confidence today?
合个影吧  因为明天早上
Take a picture, because tomorrow morning,
这些字母就要撤下来了
those letters are coming down.
我为什么要相信你真的会
Why should I believe you would even live up
实现你的承诺呢
to your end of the bargain?
因为我根本不在乎
Because I don't give a shit
你跟丹尼尔·哈德曼的斗争
about your war with Daniel Hardman.
我想要的只是看着你跪下
All I want to do is see you get down on your knees and say,
说"我退出"
"I quit."
此时此刻  狙击我们客户的公司
As of now, the company that's been targeting our clients
已经不由丹尼尔·哈德曼代理了
is no longer represented by daniel hardman.
所有支持杰西卡留下的人  举手
All in favor of jessica staying?
你到底是怎么从傅滋曼那儿拿到解约书的
How exactly did you get that termination letter for Forstman?
我同意辞职
I agreed to step down.
你不能辞职
You are not going to step down.
你为这律所付出了一切
You've given up everything for this firm.
该有人为你付出点东西了
It's time someone gave up something for you.
哈维  你不光给了我梦想
Harvey, you didn't just give me my dream.
还给了我一个家
You gave me a family.
但我终有一天会有自己的家
But I'm gonna have a family of my own someday,
我不能让这些事悬在他们头上
And I can't have all of this hanging over their heads.
你不必为我这么做
You don't have to do this for me.
我是为了我们
I'm doing it for us,
因为只要你支持我
'cause as long as you're with me--
我支持你
I'm with you.
-迈克·詹姆斯·罗斯  -怎么了
- Michael James Ross. - Yes?
你因共谋欺诈被捕了
You're under arrest for conspiracy to commit fraud.
迈克·罗斯  我是助理检察官安妮塔·吉布斯
Michael Ross, I'm assistant U.S. Attorney Anita Gibbs,
不像你  我是个正牌律师
And unlike you, I'm a real attorney.
我在见到我律师之前
I'm not answering any questions
不会回答任何问题
until I speak to my lawyer.
我听说你之前要求他来
I heard you asked for him before,
在我们静候时  我想让你知道
But while we're waiting, I just wanted to let you know
我会把你扔进监狱的
that I'm the one who's gonna put you in jail.
什么都不说
Nothing?
你可能觉得你这是无受害人犯罪
Maybe you think that you've committed a victimless crime,
但我向你保证  并不是
But let me assure you, you haven't.
据我估计  在你所谓的职业生涯中
By my estimation, you've worked on 88 legal cases
经手了88件案子
in your so-called career,
每一次你拿起电话
And you committed fraud every time you picked up the phone,
发送邮件  签名
mailed a letter, signed your name,
或者出庭  你都在诈骗
or appeared in court.
一个案件能判九个月监禁
Each instance carries a nine-month sentence,
跟你说实话吧
And to tell you the truth,
我都懒得算了
I am too tired to do the addition.
我不懒
Well, I'm not.
如果你说的是真的
If what you're saying is true
且每个案子限定为一次庭审
and there's a limit of one count per case,
那我将坐66年的牢
Then I'll be going to prison for 66 years.
我数学相当好
I've always been good at math.
我数学没那么好
Well, I haven't.
我拿手的是把像你这种
But what I am good at is putting away
虚伪自大的骗子送进监狱
fake, cocky tough guys like you
然后看着你们垮掉
and seeing them break.
因此  接下来
So here's how this is gonna go.
你要是配合  我就不难为你
You play ball, I go easy on you.
不配合的话
You don't--
就我经验看
In my experience,
上过大学的人  即使是个冒牌大学生
college boys, even fake ones,
在监狱都很难撑下来
don't do well in prison.
如果你觉得你的人
And if you think your people
正在赶来保释你
are rushing down here to bail you out,
你想多了
you've got another thing coming,
因为今晚我不会让你离开这的
because I'm gonna keep you in here all night.
行
Okay.
我会认罪的
I'll confess.
但我需要全程录影带记录
But I want the whole thing on tape.
哈维  谢天谢地  我有事跟你说
Harvey, thank god. I need to talk to you.
瑞秋  冷静一下  怎么了
Rachel, calm down. What's going on?
-迈克被捕了  -什么
- Mike's been arrested. - What?
有两个检察院的人
Two men from the U.S. Attorney's office--
直接冲他上去  逮捕了他
They just walked right up to him, and they arrested him.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
好好  不会有事的
All right. It's gonna be okay.
怎么可能没事  他现在孤身一人
It's not gonna be okay! He's by himself.
我们得想想办法
We have to do something.
我马上就去找他
I'm going down there right now.
你不能去
No, you're not.
杰西卡  这不是为了你
Jessica, this isn't up for you--
哈维  从现在开始
Harvey, from this second,
你是个没被指控的同伙
you are an unindicted co-conspirator,
我同样是
and so am I.
你也一样
And so are you,
也就是说  我们谁都担不起靠近他的风险
which means none of us can afford to be anywhere near Mike.
我不管  总有人得做点什么
I don't care. Someone has to do something.
如果这个人不是你  那就是我
And if it isn't going to be you, it's going to be me.
你会让她去
You're gonna let her go down there?
哈维  她想去就可以去
Harvey, she can knock on that door all she wants.
但他们今晚不会让她见他的
They're not gonna let her see him tonight.
再说了  她是他的未婚妻
Besides, she's his fiancée.
去见他不会让她看起上去有罪
Seeing him is not gonna make her look guilty.
我去也不会
It's not gonna make me look guilty either.
我是为了帮我兄弟
It makes me look like I'm standing by my guy.
唯一能让你看上去无罪的是
No, what's gonna keep you from looking guilty
咱俩撕了你的辞职信
is you and I ripping up your letter of resignation.
杰西卡  我和傅滋曼达成了协议
Jessica, I just made a deal with Forstman.
如果他发现我还在公司
He finds out that I'm still here,
他只要给哈德曼打个电话
He picks up the phone, calls Hardman,
他俩就能毁了整间律所
And the two of them pick this place apart.
不管是谁负责追诉这个案子
And if whoever is prosecuting this case
发现他们逮捕迈克当晚你就辞职
finds out you left on the same night they arrested Mike,
那我们还不如赶紧自首
then we may as well turn ourselves in.
这就是为什么我得
Which is why I need to get in there
作为迈克的律师去找他
And talk to Mike as his lawyer.
■
本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
那接下来事情要这样
Then this is what's going to happen.
现在你是他的律师
You are now his lawyer.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
你在这里做你要做的事
But you do whatever you have to do to work out of your house,
因为我不会告诉任何人你辞职了
because I'm not telling anybody you resigned.
这里是检察官助理安妮塔·吉布斯和迈克·罗斯
This is AUSA Anita Gibbs with Michael Ross.
现在是晚上11:05
The time is 11:05 P.M.
罗斯先生同意认罪
Mr. Ross has agreed to confess,
前提是需要录像带记录整个过程
with the stipulation that he do it on videotape.
实际上我没说要认罪
I actually never said I'd confess.
我是说我会谈谈
I said I'd talk.
你说的确实是认罪
You did say you'd confess.
也许我是说了  但同时
Maybe I did, but then again,
我在9:03时就要求见我的律师了
I also asked to see my lawyer at 9:03.
两小时过去了
It's two hours later,
而我还没有见到我的律师
and I still haven't been able to do that,
这意味着从那时到现在这段时间内
which means anything that I've said
我所说的一切都不能作为证据
between then and now is not only inadmissible,
同时这还是你侵犯了我的权力的证据
it's also evidence that you violated my rights.
我明白了  你只是想把这段录下来
Oh, I get it. You just wanted to get that on tape.
当然
Sure did.
还有  假如一小时只内我见不到我的律师
And if I don't see my lawyer in an hour,
你最好能够证明你尽了最大努力
you better be able to prove that you've made every effort
去联系他  但失败了
to contact him and couldn't.
我明白我不该知道这些事
I know I'm not supposed to know these things
因为我不是律师  但我确实知道...
because I'm not a lawyer, but I do...
因为我是律师
because I am.
好了  你玩够了吧
Okay, you've had your fun.
轮到我了
Now I'm gonna have mine.
你的律师半小时前确实出现过
Your lawyer actually did show up about half hour ago.
但关于你在哪间房间的问题上
There seemed to be a little miscommunication
出了点沟通问题
about what room you were in,
但后来一切都弄清楚了
But that's all been straightened out.
所以...
So...
他来了
Here he is.
罗伯特
Robert.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
你以为你会见到哈维·斯佩克特
You thought you were gonna see Harvey Specter
走进这间房间
come in this room
这样你俩就能对好口供了
so you two could get your stories straight.
显然这事儿不会发生了
Apparently that's not gonna happen.
通常这时我会离开房间
Now, normally this is the part where I leave the room,
但你看上去想让我留下啊
but almost looks like you want me to stay.
提醒你一句  我们没办法看到或记录
Just so you know, we can't watch or record
这里发生的任何事情...
anything that happens in here--
因为律师与当事人的特权之类的
attorney-client privilege and whatnot.
但假如你是无辜的
But if you're innocent of these charges,
我确信你没什么理由害怕
I'm sure you have nothing to fear,
单独和那个人...
being alone in this room...
待在这间房间里
with that man.
翻译：想名字好难   辰星晓Reginamoon   王大可   杨爱菜
翻译：feilixiaozi   杨爱菜   某羽校对：油炸电风扇   杨一勾
时间轴：风吹来的那片云
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第十一集
诉讼双雄
第五季  第十一集
你来这里干什么  罗伯特
What are you doing here, Robert?
瑞秋打电话给我叫我来帮你
Rachel called me and asked me to help you.
-她还好吗  -不
- Is she okay? - No.
她不好
She's not,
因为她在外面  而你在里面
Because she's out there, and you're in here.
所以你得立刻告诉我
And so you're gonna tell me right now,
这件事是真的吗
is this shit true?
听着  我可以解释一切
Listen, I can explain everything.
我不需要解释
I don't need an explanation!
我只想要那个问题的答案
I want an answer to the goddamn question.
律师不会问那个问题的
Lawyers don't ask that question.
我不是以你的律师的身份在问你
I'm not asking you as your lawyer.
我是以一个男人的身份在发问
I'm asking you as a man.
你知道答案是什么的
You know what the answer is.
该死的
God damn it.
你想要真相  现在你得到真相了
You wanted the truth, and now you got it,
但你得告诉我你来这里干什么  罗伯特
But you got to tell me what are you doing here, Robert.
我告诉你了  我来这里是因为瑞秋求我来帮你
I told you, I'm here because Rachel begged me to help you...
不是因为我关心你的情况
not because I give a shit about what happens to you.
所以你得完全按照我说的做
So you're gonna do exactly what I say,
而我会帮你从这件事里脱身
and I'm gonna help you get out of this thing.
不  没有办法从中脱身的
No, there's no getting out of this thing.
是有的  而且你也清楚这一点
Oh, yes, there is, and you damn well know it.
那女人无法从起诉你这样一个骗子中得到任何东西
That woman doesn't get anything by prosecuting a fraud like you,
但她会很乐意抓住哈维·斯佩克特的
but she would love to get Harvey Specter.
我不会背叛哈维的
I'm not turning on Harvey.
他可是会毫不犹豫地出卖你
Oh, he would do the same goddamn thing to you in a heartbeat.
假如你那样想  那是你不了解哈维
If you think that, then you don't know Harvey.
你最好听我的
You better listen to me!
你最好想想清楚了
You better get your head out of your ass,
因为我抛给了你一条救生索
because I'm throwing you a goddamn lifeline.
这是拯救你那可悲人生仅存那点东西的
It's the only chance you're gonna get
唯一机会了
to save what's left of your miserable life.
我不会这么做的
I won't do it.
那你就自求多福吧
Then you are on your own.
罗伯特  拜托了...
Robert, please--
无论你想说什么...
Whatever you're gonna say...
别说
don't say it.
事实上  你是帮了我一个忙
The truth is, you're doing me a favor,
因为在我帮你脱身之后
because after I got you out of this,
我本来会要求你在余生中都远离瑞秋的
I was gonna tell you to stay away from Rachel for the rest of your life,
但如今我不用这么做了
but I don't have to do it now,
因为不管怎样你都要蹲监狱了
because you're gonna wind up in prison anyway.
路易
Louis.
-怎么回事  -唐娜  让我进去
- What's going on? - Donna, I need to come in.
发生什么事了
What happened?
唐娜  你得坐下
Donna, I need you to sit down.
-路易  -我说了你得坐下
- Louis-- - I said you need to sit down.
哈维出什么事了
What happened to Harvey?
求求你告诉我他没事
Please tell me that he's okay.
迈克被捕了
Mike's been arrested.
天呐
Oh, my god.
-我们得去看他  -不不不
- We have to go see him. - No, no, no.
我们不能接近他
We can't go anywhere near him.
-什么  -你不能过去
- What? - You can't go down there.
路易  上帝啊  假如你背弃了迈克
Louis, so help me god, if you turn your back on Mike
然后还声称这件事和你无关...
and you claim that this has nothing to do with you--
听我说
Just listen to me.
你会想尽一切努力
You're gonna want to do everything you can
去到迈克身边  以表支持
to get to Mike and express your support,
但我告诉你
but I am telling you,
那是个坏主意
that is a bad idea.
那我得和哈维谈谈
Then I need to talk to Harvey.
不  不行
No, you don't.
你和他也得离得远远的
You need to stay the hell away from him, too,
你该庆幸你不再为他工作了
and count your blessings that you don't work for him anymore,
因为假如忽然之间
'cause if all of a sudden
你开始出现在他面前
you start showing up on his doorstep,
你就会发现自己也上了检察官的黑名单了
you are gonna find yourself next up on the prosecutor's list.
路易  我们说的是迈克和哈维啊
Louis, this is Mike and Harvey we're talking about.
他们是我们的家人
They're family.
我没在否认这一点
I am not saying they're not.
我只是说你和他们联系得越紧密
I'm saying the more contact you have with them,
情况就会对我们所有人越不利
the worse it is for all of us.
好吧  我不会过去的
Okay, I won't go down there.
但我得去看看瑞秋
But I am going to see Rachel,
假如你觉得自己阻止得了我的话
and if you think you're gonna stop me,
那你就是疯了
you are out of your mind.
我告诉你了  我是他的律师
I am telling you, I am his attorney.
假如你不让我见他
If you don't let me see him,
我就闯进去
I'm gonna break through that door.
你可以随便吵吵  但你不能进去
You can bluster all you want, but you're not getting in
因为他的律师已经在里面了
because he's already with his attorney.
-什么  -你个肮脏的龟孙子
- What? - You dirty son of a bitch.
罗伯特  冷静
Robert, calm down.
滚你妈的冷静
I'm not calming shit.
你把这个孩子带进我的生活
You brought this kid into my life.
你危及了我女儿的未来
You put my daughter's future in jeopardy.
听着  我知道你很生气...
Look, I know you're upset--
生气
Upset?
你该庆幸我没有立马宰了你
You're lucky I don't lay you out right now.
罗伯特  听我说
Robert, listen to me.
迈克·罗斯是个好人
Mike Ross is a good man.
他遇到我的时候一无所有
He came to me from nothing.
但我看到了他身上的一些品质
I saw something in him,
你也一样看到了  所以你才会在这里
and you did, too, and that's why you're here.
不  我是来让他检举你的
No, I was here to get him to turn on you,
但他太蠢了没答应
but he's too stupid to do that.
我也不知道他会不会改变主意
And I don't know if he's gonna change his mind or not,
但我已经不在乎了
but I don't care anymore,
我也不在乎能不能再见到你们任何一个
and I don't give a damn if I ever see either of you again.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
他不再是迈克·罗斯的律师了  我才是
He's not Mike Ross's attorney anymore--I am.
赶紧让我进去
So let me the hell in.
罗伯特·赞恩  真的吗
Robert Zane? Really?
我很受伤
I'm hurt.
-哈维  这一切都是来真的  -我知道
- Harvey, this is real. - I know.
我们需要弄清楚的第一件事是谁告的密
And the first we need to figure out is who tipped them off.
我们为什么要那么做
Why the hell do we need to do that?
因为如果我们想把你救出去
Because if we're gonna get you out of this,
我们需要知道他们抓住的所有把柄
we have to know every damn thing they have on you.
你疯了吗  我出不去的
Are you crazy? There's no getting out of this.
我从来没有输过官司  也不会从这件开始输
I haven't lost a case before, and I'm not about to start now.
这不是普通的官司
This isn't just some other case.
他们需要去核实线索  当他们去的时候
They're gonna check the facts, and when they do--
他们只能发现我们让他们发现的信息
They're gonna find what we let them find.
-你无法保证这点  -我可以
- You can't know that. - Yes, I can.
-你胡扯  -我没有胡扯
- That's bullshit! - This is not bullshit!
我们能赢的
Look, we can win this case.
我不在乎赢不赢
I don't care about winning this thing.
你到底有什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
哈维  我做了什么我知道
Harvey, I did this!
你什么都没做  因为他们没有证据
You didn't do shit because they don't have shit.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
迈克  哈佛的数据库里有你
Mike, you're in the Harvard database.
你有成绩单
You have a transcript.
你也考过司法考试
You're in the bar.
你是个执业律师
You're a practicing attorney.
这些都是真的
Those facts are real,
就像你一路以来办过的每一个案子
just like every case you ever worked on
帮过的每一个人一样
and every person you've helped along the way.
哈维  这个女人不是在闹着玩
Harvey, this woman's not joking.
那个女人必须证明你是个冒牌货
That woman has to show you're a fraud,
但全世界都知道  你是个律师
but as far as the world knows, you're a goddamn lawyer,
而且会一直当下去
and that's the way it's gonna stay.
别忘了
And don't forget--
我们不需要证明你是个律师
we don't need to prove you're a lawyer.
她需要证明你不是
She needs to prove you're not.
瑞秋  冷静点
Rachel, calm down.
我无法冷静
I can't calm down.
没人能告诉我任何事  我也不能去见他
No one will tell me anything. I can't go and see him.
这是他人生最糟糕的时刻
It is the worst moment of his life,
我却不能陪在他身边
and I'm not there for him.
只要允许你会去的
Well, you will be when you can.
除此之外
On top of all that,
我也不知道我爸爸去了会做什么
I don't know what my dad's gonna do when he gets there.
你打给了你爸爸
You called your dad?
瑞秋  我认为这不是个好办法
Rachel, I don't think that was a good idea.
那我也不能坐在这里什么也不做啊
Well, I couldn't just sit here and do nothing.
迈克被逮捕了
Mike's been arrested.
杰西卡在说什么未被追诉共犯
Jessica's talking about unindicted co-conspirators.
那他和哈维一定会找到解决办法的
Okay, well then, he and Harvey will just have to work it out.
如果他们找不到呢
And what if they don't?
瑞秋  我之前遇到麻烦的时候
Rachel, when I was in trouble,
哈维帮我摆脱了困境
Harvey got me out of it.
他就是干这个的
This is what he does.
听我说  他一定会帮迈克拜托困境的
I am telling you, he will get Mike out of this.
只是
It's just...
一想到他
The thought of him...
一个人在里面
in there all alone.
他不会有事的
He'll be okay.
只是一晚而已
It's just one night.
你看什么
Man, what are you looking at?
没什么
Nothing.
你上上下下的打量我
Your eyes are going up and down on me, man.
不像没什么
It don't feel like nothing.
他们都说  没什么  什么也没做
They all say, "Nothing. Wasn't doing nothing."
进了这里  说什么做什么就都不重要了
It don't matter what you say and do once you're inside.
像你这样的  在里面撑不过一周
Little snot like you won't last a week.
听见我说的了吗
You hear what I said?
你在里面撑不过一周
You won't last a week in there.
你在这也许都撑不过一夜
You might not last a night in here.
听着  伙计
Listen, man--
你个混蛋  把手拿开
Hey! Get your hands off him, you piece of shit.
算你走运  但他们不会在这里一整晚的
You're lucky, but they won't be here all night.
是啊  但你也不会
Yeah, neither will you.
没事的  没事的
Hey, it's fine. It's fine. It's fine.
不用管他  我没事的
Leave him in here with me. It's cool.
我是说  除非你准备让一个联邦法警
I mean, unless you're gonna let a federal marshal
把我打一顿然后恐吓我
beat the shit out of me just to try and scare me
达成认罪协议
into making a deal.
罗恩·达米科探员  对吧
Agent Ron Da'mico, right?
我在大厅里看到你的照片了
Yeah, I saw your picture out in the hall
接受检察院颁奖
getting a commendation from the U.S. Attorney.
当然了  照片里你没胡子
Of course, you didn't have a beard in that photo,
但在我看来长的一样
but you look the same to me.
你是个聪明人
You're a smart kid.
我想你就是这样逃过惩罚的
I guess that's how you got away with what you got away with.
但你也不算逃过了  是吧
But you didn't really get away with it, did you?
我是个法警  但下一个人就不是了
I am a marshal, but the next guy won't be,
你要是也给他摆一副无所不知的态度
and you give him that know-it-all attitude,
就像我说的  你连一晚上都撑不过
and like I said, you won't last a night.
但顺便说一句  我不会被送走的
Yeah, well, for the record, I'm not getting sent away,
就算离开  也不会进监狱
but even if I was, it wouldn't be a place like that.
如果你认为自己能去个高级监狱
Oh, if you think you're going to club fed...
那你真是太不了解安妮塔·吉布斯了
you don't know Anita Gibbs.
做个好梦  亲爱的
Sleep well, sweetheart.
他怎么样
How is he?
他被拘留了
He's in custody.
保释听证会呢
And the bail hearing?
我不知道
I don't know,
因为我不是他的代理律师
Because I'm not representing him.
你的问题问完了吗
Now, are you done asking me questions?
因为我也有一些问题
Because I have a few of my own,
比如你怎么能这样
Like how the hell could you do this?
爸爸  因为我爱他
Dad, because I love him.
那很好  但你听起来像个孩子
That's sweet, but you sound like a teenager,
你妈妈知道了以后
and right now your mother is sobbing,
一直在抹眼泪
knowing what you've done to yourself.
爸爸  迈克还是那个曾经与你共事的人
Dad, Mike is the same man that you worked with.
而且你自己也说过
And you said yourself there are things
你过去也曾做过一些难以启齿的事
that you did in your past that you're not proud of.
不要拿我和他相提并论
Don't you dare compare me to him.
我可不是骗子
I am not a fraud.
我不是罪犯
I am not a criminal.
瑞秋
Rachel...
我试图把他救出来
I tried to get him out,
但他像生活在梦里面一样
but he's living in a dream world,
如果你觉得他不会再毁掉你的生活
and so are you if you think this boy is done
那你也在做梦
ruining your life.
那你为什么还要来
Why did you even come here?
我来是想让你照照镜子
I came here to tell you to look in the mirror
然后摆脱他
and get rid of him.
我做不到
I can't do that.
那我也帮不了你
Then I can't help you.
我还在想你什么时候会来找我呢
I was wondering when you were gonna pay me a visit.
你认识我
You know who I am?
我认识我瞄准的每一个猎物
I know everyone in my crosshairs.
把奶油递给我  然后告诉我你来的目的
Now pass me the cream and tell me what you want.
我想知道你为什么在没有正当理由的情况下
I want to know why you arrested my associate
就逮捕了我的同事
without just cause.
因为迈克·罗斯是个骗子
Because Mike Ross is a fraud,
我保证会让他再也看不到
and I'm gonna make sure he never sees
法庭是什么样子
the inside of a courtroom again,
除非他穿上那件橙色的囚服上庭受审
unless he's wearing an orange jumpsuit.
至于现在  我就先失陪了
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我还有一场传讯要准备
I have an arraignment to prepare for.
如果我私下告诉你
What if I was to tell you off the record
迈克·罗斯已经打算辞职了呢
Mike Ross was about to resign?
那听起来还真是巧呢
I'd say that sounds very convenient.
不是巧合  我说的是实话
Well, it isn't. I'm telling you the truth.
如果你真的只是想
And if your interest really is
让他以后都上不了庭的话
in getting him out of the courtroom,
他其实也早有这个打算了
he was gonna do it himself.
我为什么要相信你
And why should I believe you?
我可以把他的辞职信给你
I can get you his letter of resignation.
你只要撤销指控
All you have to do is waive charges,
我就能让他同意以后永不涉足律师业
and I'll get him to agree never to practice law again.
我告诉你我会怎么做
I'll tell you what I'll do.
你把那封信给我  我就免了他的保释金
You get me that letter, and I'll waive his bail.
我不用你免保释金
I don't need you to waive bail.
不管多少钱  他付的起
Whatever it is, he can pay for it.
不  他付不起  因为我会冻结他的财产
No, he can't. I'll freeze his assets.
其实  我会让他连保释都保不了
In fact, I'll make sure that he doesn't get bail at all,
因为黑进律师资格名单是联邦犯罪
because hacking into the bar is a federal crime,
如果他有能力这么做
and if he can do that,
那他也一定可以潜逃出国
he sure as hell can flee the country.
你根本没有证据证明他黑进律师资格名单
You have no proof he hacked into the bar.
那不重要  这是他被指控的罪名
Doesn't matter. It's what he's accused of.
所以如果你想他今天能走出法庭
So you want to make sure he walks out of court today,
那就把信给我
you bring me the letter.
你最好是在打给我
That better be you calling down to my office
解释下为什么你的金童
to explain why your golden boy
昨晚因诈欺罪被捕了
was arrested for fraud last night.
我的金童
My golden boy?
是你提名他做合伙人的
You're the one that nominated him for partner.
因为你一直在否决他
Because you passed him over again and again,
我早知道这中间有猫腻
and I knew there was a reason for it,
但现在我知道是怎么回事了
but now I know what it was.
你想说什么
Just what are you implying?
没想说什么
I'm not implying anything.
你早知道那孩子是个骗子
You knew that kid was a fraud,
就算你不知道  你也有义务知道
and even if you didn't, you should have.
所以到底是怎么回事
So what is it?
究竟你是一丘之貉  还是说你根本蠢到
Are you corrupt, or are you just so stupid
连自己的律所里发生了什么都不知道
you didn't know what was going on in your own firm?
张开你的狗眼看清楚你在说谁蠢  杰克
Watch who you're calling stupid, Jack,
毕竟你才是那个投票时两手插在口袋里
'cause you were the only idiot with his hands in his pockets
出洋相的蠢货
at that vote.
以前没有得到他们的支持
I didn't have their support then,
但我现在会的  因为哈维的门徒
but I will now, because Harvey's protégé
被当众拿下带出了律所
just got perp-walked out of this firm.
而这之后  哈维也不见人影
And since then, Harvey's nowhere to be found.
哈维在哪里就不劳你费心了
Harvey's whereabouts are none of your concern.
但是其他合伙人都很上心
Well, the partners are concerned.
他们需要一个信得过的领导者
They need a leader they can trust.
我猜现在肯定有人在游说他们说
and I'll bet someone's trying to convince them
你就是那个领导者吧
that leader is you.
快看看
Well, look at that.
你对你的律所还是有点了解的嘛
You do know what's going on in your own firm after all.
给你一些上位者的建议
I'm gonna give you some advice from the throne,
免费
free of charge.
你在这家律所处于不实指控的危机关头
You attack this firm's leadership when it's in crisis
攻击领导层
over an unproven allegation...
这会让你看起来非常卑鄙
You're gonna look like a bottom-feeder.
就算他们把我投了出去
And even if they vote me out,
也不会投你入主
they sure as hell won't vote you in.
唐娜  你来干什么
Donna, what are you doing here?
格蕾琴说你有点不舒服
Gretchen told me you weren't feeling well,
所以我就顺道儿来看看你
so I dropped by to see how you're doing
然后告诉你别再编瞎话了
and tell you to cut the bullshit.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你从来没请过病假
You've never taken a sick day in your life,
现在迈克又刚刚被捕
and Mike just got arrested,
我想知道到底是出什么事了
so I want to know what the hell is going on.
我现在不能出现在办公室里
I can't be in the office right now.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为我辞职了
Because I resigned.
什么
What?
是因为迈克的事吗
Because of Mike?
因为这是唯一能让傅滋曼让步的办法
Because it's the only way to get Forstman to back off.
我才不管什么傅滋曼
I don't care about Forstman.
你要在律所最需要你的时候离开我们
You're leaving the firm when we need you the most?
唐娜  现在这个关头我必须得远离办公室
Donna, right now I have to stay away from the office,
但我不是要离开谁
but I'm not leaving anyone.
我现在是迈克的律师
I'm representing Mike.
所以你见过他了
So you saw him.
-昨晚见的  -然后呢
- Last night. - And?
他还能坚持
He's hanging in.
我只是希望这次的保释听证会顺利进行
I just need this bail hearing to go smoothly.
什么叫顺利进行  发生什么事了
What do you mean, go smoothly? What's going on?
检察官这次是要来硬的了
The prosecutor's playing hardball.
她想让他不能保释
She's trying to keep him without bail.
哈维  瑞秋已经有点不太好了
Harvey, Rachel is not doing well.
你得把他弄出来
You have to get him out of there.
那我就需要你从办公室里拿点东西给我
Then I need you to get something from the office for me.
我听说你们已经达成免除保释金的协议了
I understand you've reached an agreement to waive bail?
是的  法官大人
We have, Your Honor.
本次保释不需要保释金
No bail is requested at this time.
-你确定  -是的  我确定
- Are you sure? - Yes, I'm sure.
但是  我想要引入一项动议
However, I would like to introduce a motion
即免除斯佩克特先生担任罗斯先生的律师一职
to have Mr. Specter removed as attorney for Mr. Ross.
-什么  -以什么理由
- What? - On what grounds?
理由是他们合谋
On the grounds that they conspired
欺骗了律师协会  欺骗了他们的每一位客户
to defraud the bar association, every client they ever had,
欺骗了全体美利坚人民
and the people of the United States.
你有什么证据
What's your proof?
这封信显示罗斯先生已经打算辞职
This letter showing Mr. Ross was going to resign.
他们合谋伪造了它
They conspired to fabricate it.
-我们之前说好了的  -我不管
- We had a deal. - I don't care what we had.
他们二人打着律师委托人保密协议的名号
The two of them concocted a story
合伙捏造事实
under the guise of attorney-client privilege,
而他们之所以能这么做是因为
which they were only able to do
斯佩克特先生既是他的老板又是他的律师
because Mr. Specter is both his boss and his attorney.
我给你那封信是真心诚意的
I gave you that letter in good faith.
你给我那封信明摆着是让我
You gave me that letter in a blatant attempt
撤销对你同伙的指控
to get me to drop charges against your co-conspirator.
这分明是恶意诽谤  我不能接受
That is slander and inadmissible.
够了  到我办公室来  十分钟
That's enough. My chambers--ten minutes.
-你把那封信给她了  -我是为了捞你出来
- You gave her that letter? - I did it to get you out.
要是这会让我们俩都折进去
I don't care about getting bail
我不在乎能不能保释
if it lands us both in prison.
不会让我们俩都折进去的
It's not gonna land us in prison,
而这封信早晚得浮出水面
and it would've come out anyway.
我们不可能销毁每一件证据
We can't just destroy every piece of evidence.
我们当然不能在证据上做手脚
Oh, we can't do anything with any piece of evidence
因为她就要把你踢出局了
because she's about to get you kicked off my case.
她没有理由把我踢出局
She has no grounds to kick me off.
那封信又不是我们合伙写的
We didn't conspire to write that letter.
但我们合谋干了别的事
But we conspired to do something else,
你可别忘了
in case you forgot.
那我们最好想出别的办法
Then we better come up with something,
还得尽快想出来
and we better come up with it fast.
我可没有罢免律师的习惯  吉布斯女士
I'm not in the habit of removing counsel, Ms. Gibbs.
我也没有在审判中让同谋
And I'm not in the habit of having an accomplice
当辩护律师的习惯
be the attorney on a case.
我有请律师的权利
I'm entitled to representation.
你昨晚就已经行使过了
And you had it last night.
你登记的辩护律师为罗伯特·赞恩
Your attorney of record is listed as Robert Zane.
你想把我踢出这个案子
The only reason you want me off this case
完全是因为你能逼迫罗伯特让我的委托人
is so you can pressure Robert into making my client
接受你的烂条件
take your bullshit offer.
我想把你踢出这个案子的原因
The reason I want you off this case
是因为你是未被起诉的同谋
is because you're an unindicted co-conspirator.
如果他是未被起诉的同谋  那你也是
If he's an unindicted co-conspirator, then so are you.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你在我委托人被捕当晚
You violated my client's rights
侵犯了他的权利  有录像为证
the night he was arrested, and we have it on tape.
那完全是一个骗子的谎言
That is a complete fabrication based on the word of a con man.
一个过目不忘的所谓骗子
An alleged con man with a photographic memory,
-法官大人  -跟什么记忆有什么关系
- Your Honor. - And what does that have to do with anything?
因为如果我是谎称有录像
Because if I'm lying about a digital tape,
那我怎么会记得
then how do I know the serial number
你在审讯时用的录像机的序列号
of the camera you use in your interrogation?
RKZ986532
RKZ986532.
电池用一小片蓝色胶带粘着
Little piece of blue tape keeping the battery attached.
你是想自己撤销动议
You want to remove your motion,
还是让我传票索要那段录像
or do I have to subpoena that camera?
我会撤销动议  法官大人
I'll withdraw my motion, Your Honor.
你可以走了  罗斯先生
You're free to go, Mr. Ross,
斯佩克特先生还是你的辩护律师
and Mr. Specter is your attorney.
这只会证明你俩是一伙的
All this proves is that you two were in on this together.
这证明了你会不惜一切去胜诉
What this proves is you'll do anything to win,
现在法官和我都知道这点了
and now the judge knows it, and so do I.
路易  手头的事都放下
Louis, put down whatever you're doing.
你需要什么
What do you need?
我要你确保
I need you to make sure
公司章程里没有能让杰克·索罗夫
there's nothing in the bylaws Jack Soloff can use
用来投票踢掉我的条款
to call for a vote and get me out.
我现在就能告诉你
Well, I can tell you right now,
两周内他什么都做不了
he can't do anything for two weeks,
但两周过后  我们就没法阻止他了
but after that, there's nothing we can do to stop him.
那你得想个备用计划
Then I need you to figure out a plan B,
因为两周后...
because in two weeks--
等等  哈维怎么没来
Wait a second. Why isn't Harvey here?
什么意思
What do you mean?
这不仅是我们的律所  也是他的
I mean it's his firm as much as ours.
这一切又是因他而起
He's the one who started this whole thing,
所以他没出现肯定有原因
so there must be a reason he's not here.
哈维在为迈克辩护
Harvey's working on Mike's defense.
见鬼  那会让我们显得有罪
Oh, god damn it, that makes us all look guilty
危及我们所有人  杰西卡
and puts us all in jeopardy, Jessica.
我一开始也是这个反应
That was my reaction too.
然后我意识到
And then I realized
当辩护律师能让我们和迈克交流
this allows us to communicate with Mike and each other,
而且内容全部保密
and it's all privileged.
那你要向我保证
Then I want it said right now--
别把唐娜牵扯进去
Donna stays out of it.
没问题
That's not gonna be a problem,
因为哈维已经不是这里的律师了
because Harvey doesn't work here anymore.
-什么  -他为了让傅滋曼罢手辞职了
- What? - He resigned to get Forstman to back off.
那让我猜猜
Well, then let me guess--
不能让检察官知道他辞职了
the prosecutor can't know he did that,
也不能让傅滋曼知道他还没辞职
and Forstman can't know he didn't.
-没错  -天啊  杰西卡
- Exactly. - Jesus Christ, Jessica.
如果哈维不在  我们在杰克面前
If Harvey's not here, that even makes us
就更无力了
more vulnerable to Jack.
所以我才需要你顶上
Which is why I need you to step up
找到方法阻止那个混蛋
and figure out a way to keep that son of a bitch
把我挤下台
from taking me out.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
现在没事了
I am now.
你出来了
You're out.
我也不打算再进去了
And I have no intention of ever going back in.
我们现在要怎么办
What are we gonna do now?
我来告诉你们要怎么办
I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
我们要进攻了
We're gonna go on offense.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是要找出她知道些什么  怎么知道的
It means finding out what she knows and how she knows it.
我们要先找个地方
And it starts with us getting into a room,
列出所有知道真相的人
making a list of every goddamn person who knows the truth.
唐娜  你怎么在这儿
Donna, what are you doing in here?
我那边需要你
I need your help.
你的意思是"谢谢你加班  唐娜
Don't you mean, "Thanks for working late, Donna.
"我能求你帮点忙吗"吧
May I ask for you assistance with something?"
我的意思是杰克·索罗夫
No, I mean Jack Soloff
正踩着我们所有人往上爬呢  你得...
is crawling up our collective asses, and I need you to--
-那是什么  -私事
- What is that? - It's a private matter.
迈克·罗斯的雇佣记录
Mike Ross's employment records?
见鬼  唐娜
God damn it, Donna.
-你在帮哈维做事  -路易
- You're doing work for Harvey? - Louis--
我特地告诉你离迈克的案子远一点
I explicitly told you to stay away from Mike's case.
我听到了
And I heard you.
我就是不在乎
I just don't care.
-你说什么  -我说我不在乎
- What did you say to me? - I said I don't care.
我禁止你这么做
Well, I forbid you to do this.
什么
Excuse me?
唐娜  你好像没懂
Donna, I don't think you get it.
总有一天
There is going to come a time
你要在自己和他们之间
where you're gonna have to choose
做出选择
between yourself and them,
我不会让你为了他们俩中的任何一个
and I am not going to let you throw your life away
毁了自己
for either one of them.
你知道吗  路易
You know what, Louis?
要是他们想冲着我来  随他们来
If they're gonna come for me, they're gonna come for me.
但在那之前  如果迈克和哈维需要我
But until then, if Mike and Harvey need my help,
我就会帮忙
I'm gonna give it to them.
如果你受不了这一点
And if you have a problem with that,
你就炒了我吧
you might as well fire me.
罗伯特
Robert?
一开始瑞秋告诉我她不想为我工作的时候
When Rachel first told me she didn't want to work for me,
我们吵了一整晚
we fought all night.
我觉得没有律所能比得上我的律所
I didn't think any other firm was good enough.
然后她说要为你工作
And then she told me she was gonna work for you,
那改变了一切
and that changed everything.
一个卓越的黑人女性
A brilliant black woman,
做我女儿的导师
mentor for my baby girl,
一个能教她这个世界
someone who could teach her
会如何对待我们这种人的导师
what the world does to people like us--
教她如何在业内摸爬滚打
how to get down in the mud
却又不失尊严体面的导师
and still manage to keep her dignity.
可你看看你都教会了她什么
And look at what you taught her instead.
你就是来跟我说这些的吗
Is that what you came here to tell me?
我是来让你解雇瑞秋的
I came here to tell you to fire Rachel,
因为她不会主动辞职
because she won't quit.
等他们让他把黑锅甩给你的时候
And when they come at him to turn on you,
我得让她离这里远远的
I don't want her within 1,000 miles of this place.
抱歉  罗伯特
I'm sorry, Robert.
我做不到
I can't do that.
你清楚原因
And you know why.
我的确知道...
I do...
因为这让他看起来有罪...
Because it makes him look guilty...
而他已经有罪了
which he already is.
而且当他们让我去劝他告发你时
And when they ask me to help to get him to turn on you,
我也会极力推荐他这么做
I'm gonna recommend that he does.
你尽管做必须要做的事情
You do what you need to do,
而我也会做必须做的事来挽救我的律所
and I'll do what I need to do to save my firm.
你怎么做不重要
It doesn't matter what you do.
你的律所注定土崩瓦解
Your firm is gonna crumble all around you.
-你这是在威胁我吗  -我没必要威胁你
- Is that a threat? - I don't have to threaten you.
我连手指都不用抬一下
I don't have to lift a finger,
因为人们会从你
because people are gonna come at you
根本不知道的角落扑上来找你麻烦
from places you didn't even know existed,
而我会享受这过程的每一分每一秒
and I'm gonna enjoy every second of it.
路易  如果你要见我
Louis, if you wanted to see me,
没必要专门发短讯给我
you didn't have to send me a message
说你要在这里见我
telling me to meet you here.
我这么做是因为我有一个非常简单的
I did that because I have a foolproof plan
能让杰克还没开始就失败的计划
to stop Jack before he even gets started.
-那你说说看  -让我做管理合伙人
- Well, let's hear it. - Make me managing partner.
-再说一遍  -这是个完美的方法
- Come again? - It's the perfect solution.
我入接手  你身上的靶子就没了
I step in, target's off your back,
在事情过去前我们都能自保
and we're fine till this all blows over.
难以置信
I don't believe this.
你居然想要我的职位
You want my goddamn job.
什么  事情不是这样的
What? It's not like that.
没人会觉得我和迈克有牵连
No one thinks that I have anything to do with Mike.
我的品德无人非议
My ethics are beyond reproach.
我可不记得你的品德是无人非议的
I don't recall them being beyond reproach
想想你利用迈克的秘密让自己名字上墙的时候
when you used Mike's secret to get your name on the wall.
-杰西卡  那...  -路易
- Jessica, that... - Louis.
你只顾着自己
You are out for yourself,
我不会同意这事的
and I'm not going to stand for it.
你怎么可以对我说这话
How the hell could you say that to me
明明是你让我上位的
after you just told me to step up?
你若想帮忙
You want to step up,
就照我说的做  别再顶着
then do what I goddamn told you to do and don't come to me
迈克·罗斯的事"与我无关"的表情来找我
with some "I'm not part of this" Mike Ross bullshit ever again.
我还在想要多久你才会来找我
I was wondering how long it was going to take you.
-你听说了  -满城皆知
- You heard? - Everybody's heard.
斯科特  我有事问你
Scottie, I have something to ask you,
而这个问题会冒犯到你
and you're not gonna like what it is.
难以置信  你觉得是我干的吗
I can't believe it. You think I would do that?
不  我觉得你绝对不会这么做
No, I know you'd never do that.
那你来干吗
Then what are you doing here?
迈克觉得可能是你干的
Mike thought it could be you,
我向他保证会看着你的眼睛问这个问题
and I promised him I'd look you in the eye and ask.
好  那让我把话说清楚
Okay, so let me get this straight.
我保守了迈克的秘密  还为你弃了个案子
I keep Mike's secret, throw a case for you,
而你现在却听他的指令跑到我这
and now you're here taking orders from him
就因为你信不过我吗
because you don't trust me?
我信你  也和迈克这么说了
I do trust you, and I told Mike I did.
所以你来这儿的原因
Which is why the real reason you're here
不是问是不是我告的密
is not to ask me if I handed him in,
而是让我不要乱说
but to tell me to keep quiet.
不是强迫你...只是以防万一来请求你罢了
Not to tell you...to ask you if you're going to.
有区别吗
What is the difference?
-斯科特...  -哈维  你的生活与我无关
- Scottie... - Harvey, I am not in your life anymore.
你为什么觉得他们会找上我
I mean, what makes you think that they're going to come to me?
因为你也知道其中的流程啊
'Cause you know how this works.
他们会深挖我的私人生活
They're gonna dig into my personal life,
当他们这么做时  就会发现你
and when they do, they're gonna find you.
那有多少个女人像我这样值得你今天来拜访呢
And how many women like me are you paying a visit to today?
你是独一无二的  这点你知道的
There are no women like you, and you know that.
我只知道  上一次你来找我
What I know is, the last time you came to me,
我让你别再跟我提迈克·罗斯的名字
I told you I never wanted to hear Mike Ross's name again,
可又一次  你来我这  让我去为那个
and once again, here you are, asking me to do something
破坏我俩关系的人做事情
for the person that destroyed our relationship.
斯科特  我不是来跟你吵架的
Scottie, I'm not here to argue with you.
可你还是想知道我要怎么做吗
But you still want to know what I'm going to do?
我想
I do.
好  我想那要等他们来找我的时候
Well, I guess we're just gonna have to find that out
才知道答案了
when they come.
我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
关于婚礼的事情
Look, we've already discussed all there is
我们已经谈完了
to discuss about the wedding.
我没法去  除非你辞职...
I can't go, so unless you've quit...
我被捕了
I was arrested.
什么
What?
两天前的晚上  就在我办公室
Two nights ago, in my office,
两个美国法警毫无征兆地把我抓了
Two U.S Marshals grabbed me out of the blue.
-我很抱歉  -先留着你的抱歉
- I'm sorry. - You can save your sorrys.
我想知道是不是你告发的
I want to know if you're the one who turned me in.
什么
What?
天呐  你居然有这种想法
Jesus Christ, I can't believe you'd think that.
为什么不能有
Why wouldn't I?
这事你又不是没干过  你还告诉了沃克神父
You've done it before, and you also told Father Walker,
而且到现在我还没听到你说不是你干的
and I still haven't heard you say that it wasn't you.
好吧  不是我干的
Well, it wasn't me.
去沃克神父那儿只是为了让我的生活重回正轨
Going to Father Walker was about making things right in my life.
那行  我有办法让你和我一起回到正轨
Yeah, well, I got a way you can make things right with me.
他们会来找你
They're gonna come to you
以便立案起诉我
to put together a case against me,
我得知道你会怎么跟他们说
and I need to know what you're gonna say.
我也不知道我会说什么  迈克尔
I don't know what I'm gonna say, Michael.
你想帮我写好答案
Do you want to write down my answers for me
就像以前上课前那样吗
like you used to before class?
是啊  我想  而这次  答案会是
Yeah, I do. And this time, the answer's gonna be,
"我得先跟我的律师谈谈"
"I need to speak to my lawyer."
咱俩20年的交情就成了句"要律师"  是吗
20 years of friendship all comes down to "Lawyer up," Huh?
是啊  没错  这是你欠我的  特雷弗
Yeah, it does, and you owe me, Trevor.
我没法替你撒谎  迈克
I can't lie for you, Mike.
我不是在让你替我撒谎
I'm not asking you to lie for me.
我是在让你弥补我
I'm asking you to pay me back
弥补之前你好几次毁了我的生活
for every time in my life you have screwed me over.
好吧
Okay.
但我这样做不是为了弥补你
But I'm not doing this to make it up to you.
我这样做是为了确保我的家人
I'm doing this to make sure my family
不会被牵涉其中
doesn't get dragged into this.
别再为此事打扰我
So don't bother me with this again,
不然我可能会把我知道的对他们全盘托出
or I may just have to tell them everything I know.
看得出你出拳不错
I see you can dish it out.
问题是  你能扛得住别人打你一拳吗
The question is, can you take a punch?
不如你把拳套戴上吧
Why don't you put the gloves on?
打打就知道
We can find out.
不知道你注意到没
I don't know if you've noticed,
比赛早已开始  你我却不在一个重量级
but we're already in the ring, and you're not in my class.
你来这干吗
What are you doing here?
我只想看着你的眼睛
I just wanted to look you in the eye
问问你是否还在皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特工作
and ask if you still work at Pearson Specter Litt.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我顺路去了你办公室一趟  看看你是否
I stopped by your office to see if you were serious
真的准备要帮他脱罪  可你不在那儿
about pleading this thing out, and you weren't there.
于是我问你秘书你什么时候回来
So I asked your secretary when you'd be coming back,
她却变得很警惕
and she got very cagey.
而我现在发现你大中午在这里打拳击
And now I find you here, boxing in the middle of the day.
我来这放松一下
I'm blowing off steam.
我可不这样觉得
I don't think so.
我想你和罗斯先生伪造辞职信的事了
I think I was wrong about you and Mr. Ross
是我误会了
fabricating a letter of resignation.
应该是杰西卡·皮尔逊
And I think Jessica Pearson
发现了你们要做什么
found out what you two were up to,
比起让她自己像傻子一样
and rather than making herself look like a fool
告发你们
by handing you in,
她逼迫你们双双辞职
She forced you both to resign.
现在你们只能靠自己了
And now you're on your own.
我觉得如果你想写小说
And I think if you want to write fiction,
我听说纽约大学有辅导班
I hear they got a remedial class at NYU.
或许我想错了
Maybe I'm wrong.
或许杰西卡一直知道迈克·罗斯的事
Maybe Jessica knew about Mike Ross all along,
这样的话  或许你该告发她
in which case, maybe you would turn on her.
你不如在我揍你之前
Why don't you get the hell out of here
离开这里
before I turn on you?
我会的
I will.
但如果我发现你辞职
But if I find out you resigned,
那就是你合谋的证据
that's evidence you're a co-conspirator.
我不仅会让你打不了辩护
And I'll not only get you off this case.
还会把你和你的小宠物一起关进监狱去
I'll put you behind bars along with your little pet.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
你知道是什么  是正式通知
You know what it is. It's formal notice.
我不需要你的服务了
Your services are no longer required.
我不相信
I don't believe this.
-你要解雇我  -是的
- You're firing me? - Yes, I am.
而且我希望你今晚就收拾东西
And I want you to pack your things up tonight,
因为我们在事情轻重缓急上意见相左
because you and I don't see eye to eye on your priorities.
好  路易
Okay, Louis...
只因为我们吵了一架
Just because we had a fight--
不  这跟那个没关系
No, this has nothing to do with that.
你是说这跟你因为之前的争吵
So you're saying that this has nothing to do
而冲我发火
with you lashing out at me
完全没有关系
because of the fight we had before?
对  没有  因为在其他事上
No, it doesn't, because among other things,
你自己安排时间  不听命令
you set your own hours, you can't take dictation,
最重要的是  你根本不懂识人
and to top all that, you can't read people for shit!
到底怎么了
What's going on?
曾经你因为帮助他们而差点进了监狱
You almost went to jail for helping them once before,
我不能接受那个
and I couldn't take that.
一想到我会再次失去你...
And the thought of losing you once again...
所以你知道他们需要我帮助
So you know that they need my help.
对
Yeah.
我知道
I do.
你现在可以走了
Now you're free to go.
你为什么会改变心意
What made you change your mind?
杰西卡说我不懂团队合作
Jessica accused me of not being a team player.
她说错了  而且...
And she was wrong about me, and...
我也看错你了
I was wrong about you.
谢谢  路易
Thank you, Louis.
我得走了
I have to go.
不  路易
No, Louis.
还不能
You don't.
你们在做什么
What are you doing here?
我们那天聊到一半被打断了
Our conversation got cut short the other night.
安妮塔·吉布斯让你来告诉我
So Anita Gibbs sent you here to tell me
我要进了监狱  就不可能好好出来
that if I go to prison, I'm not gonna come out the same.
没错  是的
You're right. She did.
她想让我来吓住你
She wanted me to come here and scare the shit out of you,
告诉你在里面
tell you about everything
会发生的事情
that's gonna be happening to you inside.
谁说我会进去的
And who says I'm ever gonna be inside?
也许不会
Maybe you won't.
但只要你进去  我来告诉你
But if you do, I'm here to tell you
外面会发生什么
everything that's gonna happen on the outside.
你干嘛不赶紧滚
Why don't you get the hell out of here?
听我说  安妮塔会来找你谈协议
Listen to me. Anita's going to come to you with a deal,
而协议不会经过哈维·斯佩克特传达
and it's not gonna be through Harvey Specter.
如果你够聪明  接受它
And if you're smart, you'll take it.
我说滚
I said get the hell out.
好吧  我走  只是告诉你点事
All right, I'll go. Just let me tell you something.
联邦监狱没有夫妻探视权
They don't have conjugal visits in federal prison.
即使他们有  我也见过你未婚妻
And even if they did, I've seen your fiancée.
她很聪明  很漂亮
She's smart. She's beautiful.
她有未来
She has a future.
那样的姑娘不会等你
Girls like that don't wait around,
不管她们怎么说
no matter what they say.
-有...  -我想谈谈...
- There's-- - I wanted to talk--
抱歉  你先说
Sorry. You go first.
我爸爸来过
My father was here.
那个女人找过他  谈协议
That woman went to him and offered a deal.
我猜...
Let me guess...
他们想让我告发哈维
They want me to turn on Harvey.
他们会撤销所有指控
They'll drop all the charges,
你一分钟监狱都不用进
and you won't have to spend a minute in prison.
你怎么跟他说的
What did you tell him?
我说我会把消息告诉你
I told him that I would give you the message.
你会告诉我
That you'd give me the message?
瑞秋  你知道我不可能
Rachel, you know there's no way in hell
绝对不可能告发他  对吗
I am ever gonna turn on them, right?
-你知道的  -是的
- You know that. - Yes, I do.
-是吗  -那应该是什么意思
- Do you? - What's that supposed to mean?
意思是你应该告诉他
It means that you should have told him
我忠于我生命中的每个人
that I'm loyal to everyone in my life,
我宁愿进监狱  也不会背叛他们
and I would rather go to jail than betray them.
我告诉他了
I did tell him that.
那你为什么不跟我说你告诉了
So then why didn't you tell me that you told him that?
因为你没问我
Because that's not what you asked me.
现在告诉我你从没考虑过
Tell me right now that the idea never crossed your mind
我应该接受协议
that I should take this deal.
我当然有过那样的主意
Of course it popped into my head for a second--
所以你觉得事情一出
So you think that I should just turn on them
我就该立刻背叛他们
the second things look bad?
我没那么说
That is not what I said.
你对我也会那样吗
Is that what you're thinking of doing to me?
你怎么这么问
How could you even ask me that?
我从没想过
I never even thought for a second
你甚至会考虑背叛哈维
that you would even consider an idea so disgusting
那么恶心的想法
as turning on Harvey.
唯一能让我考虑它的原因就是
The only reason I thought about it
因为我害怕你会进监狱
is because I am scared to death
怕得要死
of you going to prison.
是害怕我进监狱
Scared of me going to prison
还是害怕你没法坚持等我
or scared that you can't stick around?
你...
Are you...
迈克  不要
Mike, don't.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
没错
Yeah, we do...
告密的不是特雷弗
'cause it wasn't Trevor.
也不是斯科特  但那不是问题所在
It wasn't Scottie either, but that's not our problem.
吉布斯今天来找我  她知道我不在律所
Gibbs came to see me earlier. She knows I'm not in the office.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是她会用那点做证据
It means she's gonna try to use it as evidence
证明哈维是同谋
of Harvey being a co-conspirator,
如果她那么做了  哈维就不能给我辩护了
and if she does that, Harvey can't represent me.
发生了什么
What's going on?
他们给迈克提供了一个协议
They offered Mike a deal.
他们希望他告发你
They want him to turn on you.
那你真是有伴了
Then you're in good company,
因为他们要我告发杰西卡
'cause they offered me a deal to turn on Jessica,
但那也不成问题
but that's not our problem.
我们的问题是得想办法让我回去
Our problem is figuring out how to get me back
而且还不能让傅滋曼知道
without Forstman finding out.
等一下
Wait a second.
傅滋曼知不知道不重要
It doesn't matter if Forstman finds out or not
只要内部没人为他做事就行了
if he doesn't have someone on the inside working for him.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我是说如果他们想让我
I'm saying that if they want me
去指认某个人
to point the finger at someone,
那就意味着我手里有枪
that means I'm holding a gun.
它还活着呢
It's still alive.
你以为我会让它死掉吗
Did you think I would let it die?
没  但我以为你会把它送人
No, but I thought you might give it away.
我比你想象中要感性
Well, I'm more sentimental than you think.
你怎么进来的
How'd you get in here?
杰西卡告诉我的
Jessica told me how
在我跟她说了我进来要干嘛之后
when I told her what I was coming here to do.
那你进来要干嘛
And what is that?
你需要我...
You need me...
因为就算格雷琴很厉害  她也不能参与这事
because as good as Gretchen is, she can't be a part of this,
你很清楚
and you know it.
你是说你要回来为我工作
You're saying you're coming back to me?
是的
Yes.
我愿意
I am.
很好
Good.
那我们明早办公室见
Then we'll see you back in the office tomorrow.
-什么意思  -意思是我要回来
- What do you mean? - I mean I'm coming back.
你怎么做到的
How did you swing that?
还没搞定  但我有个秘密武器
Hasn't happened yet, but I got a little secret weapon
叫迈克·罗斯
called Mike Ross.
那么...
Well, then...
明天见
see you tomorrow.
唐娜
Donna?
路易什么反应
How did Louis take it?
不管你信不信  这是他的主意
Believe it or not, it was his idea.
看到我很惊讶吗
Surprised to see me?
说实话  是的
As a matter of fact, I am,
不过既然你来了  我有事问你
but as long as you're here, I have a question for you.
你想知道是不是真的
You want to know if it's true.
我知道是真的
Oh, I know it's true.
我想知道你为什么没有尝试
I want to know why you haven't tried
达成协议脱离这个境地
to deal your way out of this.
你是问我为什么没有背叛哈维和杰西卡吗
You mean why haven't I turned on Harvey and Jessica?
就是这个意思
That's exactly what I mean.
这跟你想利用这事
It wouldn't have anything to do
把自己名字贴这门上[成为管理合伙人]
with you wanting to use all of this
没有关系  是吗
just to get your name on the door, would it?
不管你接不接受协议
Oh, I'm getting my name on the door
我都能把名字贴门上
whether you cut a deal or not.
如果你不停止找哈维和杰西卡的麻烦
Well, if you don't stop coming after Harvey and Jessica,
那你能看的门
the only door you're gonna be looking at
就只有带监狱围栏的了
is gonna have bars on it.
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
我来告诉你
Let me tell you
我刚刚告诉了丹尼尔·哈德曼的事
what I just got finished telling Daniel Hardman.
他们正要来抓我
They're coming at me left and right
让我承认这里有人
to admit that someone around here knew
一直都知道我的事
what was going on with me the whole time.
如果你不对这间律所
So, if you don't back off
彻底收手的话
trying to take over this firm once and for all,
我就告诉他们  那个人就是你
I'm gonna tell them that someone was you.
胡说
Bullshit.
你几个月前才刚认识的我
You didn't even know me until a few months ago.
对啊  但之后我们一起工作
Well, yeah, but then you and I worked together
办一个案子  关系那么密切
so closely on that case.
我就告诉你了
And then I confided in you.
之后你让我当上合伙人
And then you made me partner
让你自己有个盟友
so that you would always have an ally.
这种事在法庭上根本站不住脚
There's no way that holds up in court.
那你去跟法官说吧  祝你好运
Good luck telling that to the judge.
这个检察官
And this prosecutor...
她真的是变态
she--she's a real beast.
她会用尽一切手段追查你
She's gonna come after you with everything she has.
我没招惹你
I never did anything to you.
我也不会离开我的律所
And I'm not leaving my firm.
我不在乎你是去是留
I don't give a shit whether you stay or you go.
但明天哈维会回来
But Harvey is coming back here tomorrow morning,
如果你告诉了查尔斯·傅滋曼
and if you pick up that phone and call Charles forstman,
我就去找检察官
then I am gonna pick up the phone
说你和我的事
and tell that prosecutor all about me and you.
我一直好奇在这里是什么样
I always wondered what it was like in here.
比我想象得还好
It's nicer than I thought.
杰西卡  你怎么找到我的
Jessica, how'd you find me here?
你难过时总会做泥浴
You always go mudding when you're upset.
我还去射击场  还有看芭蕾
I also go to the gun range and the ballet.
你生气时去射击场
You go to the range when you're angry,
沮丧时去看芭蕾
the ballet when you're depressed,
但泥浴...
but mud...
能抚慰受伤的心
Heals the broken heart.
我知道
I know.
我听说了你和唐娜的事
And I heard about what you did with Donna.
我是来说对不起的
And I'm here to say I'm sorry.
你不是只在乎自己
You weren't just out for yourself.
但我是只在乎自己
But I was out for myself, Jessica.
唐娜让我看到的
Donna showed me that.
你是说你真的想抢我的工作吗
Are you saying you were after my job?
当然不是
Of course I wasn't.
但我他妈是在骗谁啊
But who the hell am I kidding, you know?
我不是弗罗多[《魔戒》主角]
I mean, I'm not Frodo.
一旦我获得戒指的力量
Once I got that ring of power,
我们都知道它会消耗我
We all know it would've consumed me.
我就是喜欢你这点  路易
That's what I like about you, Louis.
你也许没有自知之明
You may not be self-aware,
但只要有人举起镜子
but if someone holds up a mirror,
你就不怕去照见自己
you are not afraid to look.
谢谢你  杰西卡
Thank you, Jessica.
事实是
And the truth is,
比起我  哈维更需要唐娜
Harvey needs Donna more than I do.
那是无私又高尚的举动
Well, it was a selfless and noble act.
而在我看来  你或许不是弗罗多
And as far as I'm concerned, you may not be Frodo,
但你是山姆怀斯·甘姆齐[弗罗多的随从]
but you are Samwise Gamgee.
你...你看过《魔戒》
Get the f-- you read "Lord of the rings"?
四遍
Four times.
那书是讲权力的
I mean, it is about power.
真有意思
That's funny.
我一直觉得是关于友谊的呢
I always thought it was about friendship.
晚安  路易
Good night, Louis.
你确定不来个快速泥浴吗
You sure you don't want to have a quick mud?
或许下次吧
Maybe next time.
-真的吗  -假的
- Really? - No.
结果如何
How'd it go?
应该说杰克·索罗夫不成问题了
Let's just say Jack Soloff's not gonna be a problem anymore.
搞定一件事
That's one thing down.
是啊
Yeah, it is.
-瑞秋  -我不会离开你的
- Look, Rachel-- - I'm not gonna leave you.
你怎么知道
How can you know that?
我能说的只是我们一认识
All I can tell you is that we've managed
这事就悬在我们头上
to stay together with this thing hanging over our heads
但我们都想办法好好在一起了
for as long as we've known each other.
如果我们能撑过那一段  我们就能撑过这事
And if we can get through that, we can get through this.
但我还是可能进监狱
But I still might go to jail.
如果你进去  你会出来
And if you do, you'll get out...
而我会等你
and I'll be there.
而且那件事也不会再继续悬在我们头顶了...
And it won't be hanging over our heads...
再也不会了
ever again.